Jean-Paul Bombardier

3401 SW 1st Ave · Portland, OR 97239 · j.bombardier12@gmail.com · (503) 521-1014

————— Summary	of	Qualifications	
---------------	----	----------------	--

Offering experience managing successful statewide public policy review projects involving print and online media campaigns, and culminating in large public events. Achieved great success in designing and implementing creative outreach campaigns, building strategic partnerships and earning influential public endorsements. Strong computer skills including site development, excellent writing and editing abilities and a proven track record of establishing mind share for an emerging organization. Familiarity with the goals and practices of non-profit organizations, government agencies, and cause oriented businesses.

"The work we have done over the years has been as varied as it has been challenging. Through it all, J.P. has played a fundamental role in our most important endeavors. His leadership through our numerous projects has built widespread community support for our organization and has resulted in tangible political reform in our state."

- Elliot Shuford, Co-director, Healthy Democracy Oregon

---- Areas of Expertise ----

- Project Coordination
- Strategic Public Outreach
- Legal / Policy Research
 Copywriting
- Website Design
- Online Media Archiving Process Design
- Website Management
- Intern coordination
- Non-profit Fundraising

- Public Policy
- Event Coordination
- Messaging Development
- Office Management
- Public Communications

———— Career Achievements ————

- Developed support base of more than 40,000 Oregon voters during a two-year window through targeted online marketing and public outreach campaigns.
- Leveraged public support for organizational objectives to draft and pass groundbreaking ballot measure review bill through the Oregon State Legislature in 2009 (House Bill 2987).
- Developed strategic partnerships with other nonprofit organizations like the League of Women Voters and the Bus Project of Oregon to further political legitimacy and influence.

----- Professional Experience -----

HEALTHY DEMOCRACY OREGON - Portland, OR

Outreach Coordinator, Director of Research for a non-profit organization dedicated to ballot measure reform. (January 2008 – December 2010)

- Develop and implement multidimensional outreach campaign to build both awareness of, and public support for, the organization and its goals.
- Lead team of graduate interns through policy research assignments and produce consultative reports for co-directors and board.
- Design, develop and maintain organization's online presence, including: social media outlets, Drupal homepage upkeep, media archive creation, blog posting, ad buying, supporter database management, and message board promotion.

————— Professional Experience (continued) —————

- Cultivate organizational messaging platform and author fact sheets, public correspondence, FAQ
 page, regular newsletters, editorial content, and boilerplate language for letters to the editor and
 lobbying campaigns.
- Track statewide politically significant events and coordinate organization's participation.
- Serve as organization's public point-of-contact person.
- Identify and recruit high-level experts for their support and participation in ballot measure review proceedings.
- Coordinate and manage high-profile ballot measure review projects concerning various policy issues.
- Lobby state legislators for their support.

THE JEFFERSON CENTER – Minneapolis, MN

Project Coordinator for non-profit organization conducting citizen juries on policy issues. (December 2008 – June 2009)

- Establish identification and recruitment procedures for developing a demographically representative group of voters to participate in ongoing policy discussions.
- Sell event and organizational goals to skeptical members of the public and convince them to participate.
- Develop educational materials for use during policy discussions.
- Conduct policy research to inform the citizen jury.
- Recruit experts and member of the legislature for their support and participation.
- Coordinate with other non-profit organizations working towards common goals.

PROMOTING HEALTHY DEMOCRACY - Seattle, WA

Project Coordinator for non-profit organization committed to designing and conducting public democratic reforms. (June-July 2010)

- Design new procedures for educating members of the public on facts related to specific policy issues.
- Research presentation methods to produce better public engagement with information.
- Test new procedures with panel of randomly selected Washington voters.
- Analyze results of test to inform future public education efforts.

UNITED STATES BANK - Springfield, OR

Community Banker (April 2006 – January 2008)

- Recruit business and personal banking customers to expand branch account holdings.
- Assist business customers with financing operating expenses using various credit products.
- Intake and underwrite home mortgage, refinance, and auto loans.
- Manage team of junior bankers and tellers.

Education

UNIVERSITY OF OREGON – Eugene, OR
School of Architecture and Allied Arts
Bachelor of Science in Planning, Public Policy & Management • 2008
Graduated with Honors

PORTLAND STATE UNIVERSITY – Portland, OR School of Business Administration Graduate Certificate in Real Estate Development • 2010